地         球         脉         动   I I
想象一个世界
Imagine a world
气温高达50摄氏度
where temperatures rise to 50 degrees Centigrade.
没有什么能阻挡烈日  狂风与沙尘
Where there's no escape from sun, wind and dust.
想象一个世界  几乎没有食物和水
Imagine a world with almost no food or water.
这种地方占据了
These are the conditions
地球上三分之一的土地
in one third of the lands of our planet.
生长于斯  必须掌握非凡的生存策略
To live here demands the most extraordinary survival strategies.
沙        漠
这是世界上最古老的沙漠
This is the oldest desert in the world.
画 外 音
大卫 · 爱登堡   爵士
纳米布沙漠  位于非洲西南部
The Namib in south-west Africa.
干旱已经持续了五千五百万年
It's been dry for 55 million years.
对于捕食者来说  生活异常艰难
Life here for a hunter is as hard as it gets.
一群狮子
A pride of lions.
她们是极少数能够忍受如此
One of the very few that endures this desert's
高温缺水的沙漠环境的物种之一
scorching temperatures and lack of water.
沙漠狩猎有着特殊的难题
Hunting here presents special problems.
这群直角大羚羊
A herd of oryx,
是方圆三十二公里内唯一的猎物
the only prey within 20 miles.
这里没有任何伏击可用的遮挡物
Out here, there is no cover for an ambush.
唯有直截了当扑杀过去
It'll have to be a straight chase.
她们失败了
They have failed
每失败一次  狮群离饿死就更近一步
and each failed hunt brings the lions closer to starvation.
为了寻找食物充饥
To find enough to eat,
狮群不断地在瑞士国境那么大的区域内搜寻
the pride continually searches an area the size of Switzerland.
三天里它们走了一百六十一公里  仍然一无所获
Three days and 100 miles later, and still no kill.
这是濒临绝望的时刻
These are desperate times.
她们领土的边缘有一条干涸的河床
A dry riverbed on the edge of their territory.
长颈鹿是附近唯一的动物
The only animals here are giraffe,
但这重达一吨的巨兽一脚就能踢死一头狮子
but these one-tonne giants could kill a lion with a single kick.
狮群很少会去叨扰如此棘手的猎物
Lions seldom tackle such formidable prey...
但没有食物充饥  狮群已寸步难行
...but this pride can't go on much longer without food.
为了猎杀成功
The whole pride must work together as a team
整个狮群必须互相配合
if they're to succeed.
两头母狮带头追捕
Two lionesses lead the chase.
其他狮子奋起直追  切断猎物的逃生路线
Others race to cut off possible escape routes.
长颈鹿的速度和耐力都强于狮群
The giraffe has the speed and stamina to outrun the pride...
但它正被逐入敌人的陷阱
...but it's being chased into a trap.
领头的母狮就在前面等待着
Up ahead, the lead female waits.
轮到她上场了
It's now up to her.
狮子的猎杀行动多以失败告终
Most lion hunts end in failure.
但沙漠种群的失败次数远比其他种群要多得多
But no lions fail more often than those that live in the desert.
狮群必须再次踏上寻找食物的征程
Once again, the pride must continue their search.
沙漠地区偶尔也会降雨
It does, sometimes, rain in the desert.
在美国西部地区
Here, in the American West,
暴风雨会带来灾难性的影响
storms can strike with devastating force.
十个月的干旱以后
After ten months of drought,
百万吨降水
millions of tonnes of water
在一小时内倾泻而下
are dumped on the land in under an hour.
数百万年来
Over millions of years,
挟带着砂石的湍急洪水
sand and gravel carried by the rampaging floods
在坚硬的岩石上切割出凹槽
have carved channels through the solid rock.
形成狭缝谷  深达四十六米
Slot canyons, 150 feet deep.
一些地方的峡谷不断侵蚀扩张
In some places, these canyons have widened
最终形成桌状高地
until the land between them is sculpted into tablelands
和高耸的石塔
and isolated pinnacles,
这是地球上最激动人心的自然奇观
some of the most dramatic landscapes on the planet.
雨季也许早已过去
The rain may be long gone...
但沙漠里还是有水
...but there is water here...
只是储存在沙生植物特化的组织当中
...locked away within the tissues of specialist desert plants.
仙人掌是美国沙漠中独一无二的植物
Cacti are unique to American deserts.
它们肥硕的茎干
They all hoard water,
有储水功能
storing it in swollen stems
叶片特化成刺以防止水分散失
and protecting it behind a barricade of spines.
这套策略成功地让它们主宰着这片沙漠
They're so successful that they dominate these deserts.
但这片尖刺丛林也给居住在此的动物们
But this forest of spikes can cause problems
带来了很多麻烦
for the animals that live here.
一只栗翅鹰
A Harris' Hawk.
它练就了在仙人掌林捕食的特殊技能
It has developed special techniques for hunting amongst the cacti.
这是地松鼠
Ground squirrels.
栗翅鹰的猎物
Prey.
当发现危险信号时
At the first sign of danger
地松鼠们迅速躲进刺丛中避险
they bolt for the safety of the thorns.
但栗翅鹰有法子逼它们出来
But the hawks have a tactic to flush them out.
栗翅鹰是唯一成群捕食的猛禽
These are the only birds of prey that hunt in packs.
它们编队飞行
Flying in formation,
将猎物驱赶到开阔地带
they try to drive their quarry into the open.
但这只地松鼠按兵不动
But this squirrel is staying put.
栗翅鹰开始改变策略
So now the hawks continue the hunt...
转为地面追击
...on foot.
它们从四面八方逐渐逼近
They're closing in from all sides.
很快封锁了所有的逃跑路线
Soon, all escape routes are cut off.
地松鼠陷入绝境
The squirrel is trapped.
这片沙漠上的植物几乎都浑身是刺
The spines that cover almost every plant in this desert
它们能为动物提供了庇护之所
can provide protection and shelter for many animals.
可这些尖刺上为什么挂着尸体
So, why should these spikes be hung with corpses?
如此可怕的场景究竟
What kind of creature could be responsible
是谁的手笔呢
for creating such a gruesome scene?
这片沙漠里有一位神秘杀手
There's a mysterious killer at work in this desert.
一只伯劳鸟
It's a butcherbird.
就像屠夫用钩子挂肉
This little songbird uses the spines
这只小型鸣禽利用这些刺
as a butcher uses his hook...
将肢解完的食物悬挂起来
to hold its prey as it dismembers it.
幼鸟们嗷嗷待哺  叶刺就像是食品储藏柜
And with chicks to feed, he also uses the spines as a larder.
他已经储备了好几个星期
He's been stocking it for weeks.
把猎物挂起来可以防止地面的食腐动物来争抢
Hanging his prey out of the reach of scavengers on the ground
以确保刚出生的幼鸟不会挨饿
ensures that his newly hatched young will never go hungry.
为了让好时光持续更久点
An ingenious solution
这的确是个巧妙的策略
to making the good times last in the desert...
虽然有点毛骨悚然
...if a little macabre.
有的荒漠十分贫瘠
Some deserts are so arid,
看似寸草不生
they appear totally devoid of all vegetation.
但即使是这种地方也能在几天之内焕然新生
Yet even these landscapes can be transformed in a matter of days.
秘鲁荒漠是世界上最干燥的地方之一
The deserts of Peru are amongst the driest in the world,
休眠了几个月的植被  只要遇到一点点水
but just add a little water and plants that have lain dormant for months
便可立即恢复生机
will burst into life.
当沙漠突然变为绿洲
And when a desert suddenly turns green,
即使看似最荒凉的地方
even the most seemingly desolate
也能变得生机勃勃
can become a land of opportunity.
没有什么生物能比蝗虫更早或更轰动地
No creature exploits the greening of a desert more quickly
发现这抹绿意
or more dramatically than a locust.
马达加斯加干旱的西南部
Madagascar's arid south-west
迎来了近几年最大的降雨
has received its highest rainfall in years.
蝗虫大军正大步行进
Now, an army is on the march,
追寻着新生嫩芽的香气
attracted by the smell of newly sprouting grass.
蝗虫通常独居
Locusts are normally solitary creatures,
但当食物突然充足之时
but when food becomes suddenly plentiful
它们便聚集成群  以势不可挡的气势
they come together into an unstoppable force
吞噬沿途所有的植物
that devours everything in its path.
而这巨大的灾难正愈演愈烈
But this devastation is about to get a lot worse.
蝗虫正在变态为有翅的成虫
The locusts now transform into winged adults,
由于生长环境良好
and with conditions as good as this,
它们发育的速度达到平时的三倍
they do so three times faster than normal.
现在到了食欲最旺盛的时候
Now they are at their most voracious...
有了翅膀  它们就能飞行
and with wings, they can take to the skies.
一旦上天  蝗虫每天可以飞行九十六公里
Once airborne, the locusts can travel over 60 miles a day
去寻找新的觅食区
in their search for new feeding grounds.
如此大规模的超级蝗群也许十年才出现一次
A super swarm of this scale may only appear once in a decade.
这个蝗群遍布五百一十八平方公里
This one extends over 200 square miles
共有数十亿只蝗虫
and contains several billion individuals.
每天能吃掉四万吨食物
Between them, they will devour 40,000 tonnes of food in a day.
蝗灾吞噬植被的速度和彻底性
Nothing can strip a land of its vegetation with such speed
没有任何事物能与之比肩
and thoroughness as a plague of locusts.
当食物消耗殆尽时  蝗虫大军就会灭亡
When the food eventually runs out, the whole army will die...
但不等它们寂灭下来  世界早已一片狼藉
but not before it's devastated the land.
没有植被固定土壤
With no plants to bind them,
稀薄的土层很快就会变成沙尘  被风吹走
thin soils soon turn to dust and blow away.
如今  这片不毛之地只能任由自然力量摆布
Now, these barren lands are left to the mercy of the elements.
烈日炙烤加之风沙侵袭
Scorched by the sun and scoured by windblown sand,
沙漠岩石形成了奇异非凡的景致
desert rock is shaped into strange, otherworldly landscapes.
这片岩质沙漠或许看似美好
These rocky deserts may have a beguiling beauty,
但这里如此荒芜  极少生物能够适应
but when they become this barren, very little life can endure.
动物们想要在最严苛的环境里活下来
For many animals, the only way to survive the most hostile times
就必须不断迁移
is to keep moving.
喀拉哈里沙漠短暂的雨季已被旱季替代
In the Kalahari, brief rains have given way to the dry season.
食物和水愈发稀缺
Food and water are becoming increasingly scarce.
这群斑马是时候离开了
For these zebra, it's time to leave.
斑马的迁移距离称霸
They're setting off on the longest overland migration
所有非洲哺乳动物
made by any mammal in Africa,
嗅着远方雨水的味道不断前进
marching towards the scent of distant rains.
随着干旱加剧
As drought intensifies,
沙漠象也必须踏上旅途
desert-living elephants must also undertake long journeys
寻找水源
in search of water.
年长的母象能记住哪些地方
The older females can remember where,
即使在极端干旱的季节也会有水
even in times of extreme drought, there may still be water
有时她能把象群带领到
and sometimes lead the herd to a water hole
数十年前去过的水坑
they may not have visited for decades.
这群斑马即将结束旅程
These zebra are almost at the end of their journey.
这里就是它们的目的地
This is what they've been heading for...
一个珍贵的水坑
...A rare water hole.
沙漠里的大部分水坑都转瞬即逝
In deserts, most water holes are short lived.
它们在雨后出现
They appear after rains,
但以几乎同样的速度消失
but then vanish almost as quickly as they came.
动物长途跋涉来到这里
Animals have come here from many miles around.
但在此地逗留可能会有危险
Yet this can be a dangerous place in which to linger.
离水坑九十六公里远的沙漠中心
60 miles away, in the heart of the desert,
沙鸡的雏鸟正在孵化
sandgrouse chicks are hatching.
他们待在这里比较安全
It's safer for them to be here.
但是离水源那么远  也有很大风险
But being so distant from water is a gamble.
只有母亲在帮他们遮挡太阳
With only their mother to shield them from the sun,
如果没有水喝  雏鸟会在数小时内曝晒而死
if they get nothing to drink, they will be dead within hours.
唯一的希望寄托在父亲身上
Their only hope is their father.
每天早上  他都要往返飞行一百九十三公里
Every morning he makes the 120-mile round trip
为家人带水回来
to get water for the family.
沙鸡从四面八方飞来这片绿洲
Grouse from all over the desert visit this oasis,
在这里集结成群
arriving together in large flocks,
这十分重要
and that is important.
数量越多越安全
There's safety in numbers.
雄沙鸡抓紧时间喝了口水
The male snatches a drink,
但他还要给雏鸟们带水回去
but he also needs to collect water for his chicks.
他胸前特化的羽毛
Using specially adapted breast feathers,
可以像海绵一样吸收大量的水
he can soak up water like a sponge.
不过这需要时间  而他已身陷危险
But it takes time, and he is in danger.
苍鹰
Goshawk.
沙鸡是他们的主要猎物
Sandgrouse here are their main prey.
日复一日  雄沙鸡都要冒着生命危险
Again and again, the male sandgrouse risk their lives
来给雏鸟采水
in order to collect water for their chicks.
这就是沙鸡巢离水坑如此远的原因
This is why sandgrouse nest so far from water holes.
终于  他吸足了水
At last, he's soaked up as much as he can.
带着自身体重四分之一的水
Carrying a quarter of his body weight in water,
他开始漫长的归家旅程
he can now set off on the long journey home.
到家了  时间刚刚好
He's back, and just in time.
雏鸟可以喝上第一口水了
He can give the chicks their first ever drink.
但在未来两个月  他依然每天都要
But he will have to undertake this perilous journey every day
踏上这段危险的征程
for the next two months
直到雏鸟长大
until his chicks can finally make the flight
能独自飞到水坑
to the water hole for themselves.
美国西部内华达州沙漠的七月
It's July in the deserts of Nevada in the western United States.
是一年中最炎热的时候
The hottest time of the year.
一群群美洲野马聚集在
Bands of wild horses, mustang, are converging on
方圆几公里内仅存的水塘边
one of the last remaining water holes for miles.
水不仅能用来喝
Now, water not only offers them the chance to drink,
还能借此获得权力
it can also bring power.
如果一头公马能够控制饮水权
If a stallion can control access to water,
便拥有与群中所有母马交配的权利
he will have secured mating rights to the entire herd.
所以公马们会试图独占水塘
So stallions try to dominate these pools,
赶走所有想要靠近的竞争对手
fighting off rivals who venture too close.
一位不速之客
A stranger.
他跋涉了十六公里
He's travelled ten miles to be here
因为他所在地方的水源已经完全干涸
because the pools where he's come from have already dried up.
他身后跟着一群母马
With him come his females.
如果他无法提供水源  她们都会离开
If he can't provide them with water, they will leave him
跟这匹已经占有水池的白马在一起
for the white stallion who already dominates this pool.
他必须选择战斗
So, he will have to fight.
这一战至关重要
There is everything to lose.
若是断了腿  或是碎了下巴
A broken leg or a shattered jaw
就意味着死前将饱受折磨
would mean a slow and painful death.
没踢中  一切都结束了
A missed kick, and it's all over.
新来的马取得了胜利
The new arrival has won...
他所获得的奖赏不只是可以喝水
and his prize is more than just the chance to drink.
他为马群提供了水源  与此同时
He has provided for his herd, and in the process,
抢走了竞争对手的后宫
stolen his rival's females.
白马的统治已经结束
The white stallion's rule is over.
沙漠中不仅水源稀缺
Desert life is not only shaped by the scarcity of water,
更有炎炎烈日的残酷炙烤
but also by the relentless power of the sun.
地球上的最高温度记录
The highest temperatures on Earth
全部出现于沙漠中
have all been recorded in its deserts.
气候变化让这里的温度
Changes in the climate mean temperatures here
涨幅和速度都超过全球平均值
are rising more than the global average,
随着温度升高  沙漠也在不断扩散
and as deserts heat up, they are also expanding.
每年都有近十三万平方公里的草地和农田
Every year, a further 50,000 square miles of grass and farmland
变成了贫瘠干涸的尘土沙石
are turning into barren stretches of dust and rock.
一天中最热之时
In the heat of the day,
沙漠地表温度可达七十一摄氏度
surface temperatures can reach 160 degrees,
大多数生物都无法忍受
far too hot to handle for most.
但这只铲吻蜥蜴却可以
But not for this shovel-snouted lizard.
它将四肢轮流抬起
Raising its feet off the ground in turn...
短暂降温一下
...enables each to briefly cool.
可即便是这位耐热性极强的沙漠舞者
But even this dancing desert specialist
也无法长时间忍受高温
can't stand the heat for long.
一个办法是寻找阴凉
One option is to find shade.
沙丘草是这里唯一的植物  近乎无荫可寻
Dune grass, the only vegetation here, provides virtually none,
但仅仅是沙子表面下几厘米处
but just an inch beneath the surface of the sand,
温度都要低上几度
it is several degrees cooler.
为躲避难耐的高温  沙漠动物有了自己的节奏
Avoiding the extreme heat imposes a rhythm on desert life.
许多动物都选择了最简单的解决方案...
And many animals here choose the simplest option of all...
白天隐匿在各处
staying hidden all day,
只在凉爽的夜晚外出活动
and only venturing out in the cool of the night.
夜幕降临  动物纷纷从各处冒出
As darkness falls, animals appear from seemingly nowhere.
而这之中  必然存在
And, among them, inevitably,
猎食者
are hunters.
其中最贪婪的夜间捕食者
One of the most voracious nocturnal predators
也最难寻觅它们的踪迹
is also one of the hardest to see.
这个神秘的生物
This mysterious creature
鲜少出现在沙丘表面
hardly ever appears on the surface of the dunes.
但沙子的移动  却泄露了它的行踪
But there are signs on the sand that can give it away.
它只生活在
It lives only here,
沙粒干燥光滑的地区
where the sand grains are so perfectly dry and polished,
让它们可以如流水般行动自如
that they flow almost like water.
它的体型还没有乒乓球大
It's no bigger than a ping-pong ball.
一只金毛鼹鼠
A golden mole.
它的视力已完全退化
It's totally blind,
但地下本来也没有什么可看的
but there's nothing to see underground anyway.
取而代之的是它极佳的听觉
Instead, it has superb hearing.
它的头犹如扩音器
Its entire head acts as an amplifier
能够捕捉通过沙子传来的振动
that picks up vibrations through the sand,
所以  为了定位沙丘表面上的猎物
so, to locate prey on the surface of the dune,
它反而矛盾地将脸埋进沙子里
it has, paradoxically, to thrust its face into the dune.
白蚁
Termites.
双目失明自然不太好捉
Not easy to catch when you're blind.
最好还是切换成隐身模式
Far better to go into stealth mode.
一旦潜入沙中
Once below the sand,
金毛鼹鼠可以感知微弱的震动
it can detect the slightest movement...
让它能发动精准袭击
allowing it to strike with pinpoint accuracy.
大多数时候是这样
Well, most of the time.
它们一晚可以行进1.1公里
They can travel two thirds of a mile a night
来寻找晚餐
in search of its dinner...
现在  它刚刚发现了自己的主菜
and right now, it has just detected its main course.
难怪它有时候被称作“沙丘之鲨”
Little wonder it's sometimes called "The shark of the dunes".
食物在沙漠中非常稀缺  即便是在夜晚
Food can be so scarce in the desert that, even at night,
动物们也无权挑剔自己的饮食
animals can't afford to be choosy about what they eat.
在以色列的内盖夫沙漠
Israel's Negev desert.
中东尖耳蝠  沙漠中的长耳蝙蝠  正在捕猎
Otonycteris, the desert long-eared bat, is on the hunt.
大多数蝙蝠在飞行中捕捉飞虫
Most bats catch flying insects on the wing,
但在沙漠中飞虫数量极少
but there are so few of these in the desert
这只蝙蝠必须另寻他路
that this bat must do things differently.
它必须在地面捕猎
It has to hunt on the ground.
但真正让它与众不同的是它的猎物
But what really sets it apart is what it's hunting...
一只以色列金蝎
A deathstalker scorpion.
这种蝎子的毒液足以毒死一个人
The venom of this species is potent enough to kill a human.
捕捉毒蝎对于仅有十四克重的蝙蝠来说近乎疯狂
Tackling it seems madness for a bat weighing just half an ounce.
周围一片漆黑
In the pitch-black,
猎食者和猎物都丧失了视力
both predator and prey are effectively blind,
但是蝎子有一项优势
but the scorpion has one advantage...
他能够通过沙子的振动
he can sense the approach of the bat
感知到蝙蝠的靠近
through vibrations in the sand.
尖耳蝠则要完全依靠自己的听觉
Otonycteris must rely entirely on its hearing.
如果蝎子不动  它就无法感知其位置
If the scorpion doesn't move, it won't know it's there.
战斗打响了
The battle is on.
凭借强大的双钳和一根毒刺
Armed with crushing pincers and a sting loaded with venom,
这只毒蝎是一个危险的对手
this scorpion is a dangerous opponent.
蝙蝠脑袋遭到一记猛刺
A direct strike on the head.
战斗结束了吗
Is it all over?
对这只蝙蝠来说并没有
Not for this bat.
尖耳蝠显然对毒液有一定的免疫
Otonycteris clearly has some immunity to the venom,
但连续的猛刺给它带来了难言的剧痛
but repeated stings must still be extraordinarily painful.
如果这只蝙蝠不想挨饿
And if the bat is not to go hungry,
它必须在日出之前再抓住三只蝎子
it must catch another three scorpions before sunrise.
沙漠动物进化出了非凡的策略
Desert animals have developed remarkable strategies
来充分利用难得的良机
to make the most of the rare opportunities that come their way.
虽然有些沙漠也许数年都不会下雨
Although some deserts may not see rain for several years,
但大多数都会以各种形式储存少量的水分
most will hold a little water in one form or another.
诀窍在于如何获取水分
The trick is simply knowing how to reach it.
破晓时分  纳米布沙漠的沙丘上
Dawn in the dunes of the Namib,
神奇的现象正在发生
and something magical is happening.
大西洋沿岸上空的湿空气
Moist air lying over the neighbouring Atlantic
冷却并被吹至内陆
is cooled and blown inland,
形成雾堤  笼罩沙漠
forming fog banks that shroud the desert in mist.
这些珍贵的水汽诱人地弥漫在沙丘顶部
This precious moisture lies tantalisingly out of reach
难以触及  而且不会久留
at the top of the dunes, and it won't last long.
太阳升起数小时后就会被烤干
It'll be burnt off by the sun just hours after it rises.
拟步甲狂奔至沙丘顶部
Darkling beetles race to the top of the dunes
要赶在薄雾消失之前吸收水分
to reach the fog before it vanishes.
纳米布的沙丘有些高达三百米
Some of the Namib's dunes are 1,000 feet high,
堪称世界之最
the tallest in the world.
对于拇指盖大小的甲虫来说  攀爬距离相当于
For a beetle no larger than a thumbnail, this is the equivalent
人类攀爬一座比珠穆朗玛峰高两倍的沙丘
of us climbing a dune twice the height of Everest.
但更令人印象深刻的是它接下来的举动
But even more impressive is what it does next.
身体正直  迎面朝风
Standing perfectly still, facing into the wind,
甲虫倒立在沙丘上
the beetle does a headstand.
薄雾开始在它身上凝结成水滴
Fog begins to condense on its body.
鞘翅上的小凸起
Microscopic bumps on its wing cases
将水引到通向嘴部的一个小沟渠里
direct the water to grooves that channel it towards the mouth.
在回到背风坡上之前
Before returning down the slip face,
它要喝下百分之四十体重的水分
it will drink 40% of its body weight.
这只小甲虫学会了
This little beetle has learned
如何在地球上最干燥的地方之一
how to conjure water out of the air
从空气中变出水来
in one of the driest places on earth.
然而它并非沙丘顶部唯一的访客
And it's not alone on the top of the dunes.
蹼趾虎也采用了相似的办法
Web-footed geckos use a similar trick.
肯定少有动物跋涉更远的距离去获取水分
Surely, few animals go to greater lengths to get a drink.
不幸的是  纳米比亚变色龙知道在薄雾弥漫的早晨
Unfortunately, Namaqua chameleons know that on foggy mornings,
从沙丘上下来的甲虫
the beetles coming down the dunes
会比上去的更多汁
are juicier than those going up.
在这样一个水资源完全匮乏的世界
The diversity of life that thrives in a world
生物多样性如此之高  确实令人惊叹
almost totally devoid of water is truly remarkable.
在沙漠中成功存活
Success in the desert
依靠的是数百万年进化而来的
depends on an extraordinary variety of survival strategies
非凡多样的生存策略
that have evolved over millions of years.
但我们的地球正遭受着变故
But our planet is changing.
世界沙漠的面积在扩大  温度更高  更加干燥
The world's deserts are growing bigger, hotter and drier,
而且在以史无前例的速度变化着
and they're doing so faster than ever before.
沙漠生命在未来如何存活  依旧有待观察
How life will cope here in the future remains to be seen.
下一集  我们将探访地球上的平原
Next time, we journey to the world's great plains,
壮观的野生动物群在那里适应着极端的变化
where spectacular gatherings of wildlife cope with extreme change...
而奇妙的生物  有着意想不到的生存方式
...and surprising creatures survive in unexpected ways.